<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eclectic Neurons</title>
    <link>https://hirico.moe/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eclectic Neurons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 22:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hirico.moe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Understanding</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 22:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/understanding/</guid>
      <description>When we are talking about understanding a subject, it&amp;rsquo;s important to recognize that understanding has different levels and different aspects.
One way to gauge one person&amp;rsquo;s understanding is to see what questions about the subject can he/she answer. Take React Flux for example: what are the signatures of its APIs? What problem is it trying to solve? What characteristics of React/Web determine its necessity? Who invented it? What is its pros &amp;amp; cons?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why open source contribution is hard</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/whyopensourceishard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/whyopensourceishard/</guid>
      <description>This article is based on my reflection on one of my pull requests.
My pull request is to resolve an usability issue of Visual Studio Code. Basically, if you opened a file in vscode and clicked &amp;lsquo;view its changes from version control system&amp;rsquo;, a sidewindow showing its last version would appear so you could compare the two versions. The problem was that your previous view position of the file was not preserved, and the vscode would scroll your screen to the cursor position of the file, which surprised the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scope, Belief and Value</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/sbv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 20:15:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/sbv/</guid>
      <description>I once thought the notion of narrowing your scope is only a term amongst incompetent researchers, and real masters will address large, interdisciplinary, nuanced problems in sound ways.
Turns out I was biased by public-oriented materials. Senior intellectuals communicate their grand thoughts, philosophies and opinions via public platforms like social media, blogs and talks, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean their published works which built their recognition are grand.
Intellectuals could easily let any grand theory fall apart, due to we human&amp;rsquo;s limited and brittle knowledge about the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Dreams</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/rinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 11:07:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/rinterest/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes find some of my research interests too broad and futuristic, so I call them my research dreams.
While the fundamental ideas about programming haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much, in order to create a modern application, the learning barrier accumulated from small techniques is dreadful. Just look at the web: in 2017, you need to learn 9 different techniques to write a modern web application, even if you already own a related degree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why students find Stack Overflow useful, and when they don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/sosurvey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 14:50:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/sosurvey/</guid>
      <description>In one of my junior optional courses, I conducted a simple survey in the form of homework to ask my classmates&amp;rsquo; experience about Stack Overflow. They are all my peers at the Software Institute, who have extensive experience of developing large and new software projects (therefore use Stack Overflow a lot) compared with more traditional CS students.
There were two questions in the survey:
 Under what circumstances do you want to use Stack Overflow?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language and thinking</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/thinkinglanguage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/thinkinglanguage/</guid>
      <description>When we ruminate, how intensely should we use language?
Based on my experience on EL (a game development competition) and many other thrilling moments, it&amp;rsquo;s often when I break the frame of language, take the underlying instinct, and let the instinct flow in its natural way, that I feel most productive and powerful.
But using language has its own benefit. Language is paradigm, which helps us confine thoughts to successful patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmatched Speed</title>
      <link>https://hirico.moe/post/unmatchedspeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hirico.moe/post/unmatchedspeed/</guid>
      <description>When I write code, it happens now and then that I forget some syntax or API, and typically I will ask google (type the question in the chrome address bar) instead of checking documentation.
When I use my laptop with a mouse connected, I often turn to touchpad to accomplish small tasks. It’s known that some veteran programmers don’t use either, keeping their hands on the keyboard.
Why would I make these decisions?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>